<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notebooks on Mae Saslaw</title>
    <link>https://saslaw.github.io/notebooks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notebooks on Mae Saslaw</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saslaw.github.io/notebooks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shiny apps with GNIP data</title>
      <link>https://saslaw.github.io/notebooks/shiny-apps-with-gnip-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saslaw.github.io/notebooks/shiny-apps-with-gnip-data/</guid>
      <description>(in progress)
This is a collection of links to basic Shiny apps using data from the Global Networks of Isotopes in Precipitaion (IAEA/WMO, 2020). Apps are hosted on shinyapps.io, and some of the code can be found across my GitHub repos.
Level 0 My first app uses the RStudio sample Shiny code to create an adjustable histogram, with data from GNIP instead of “Old Faithful” sample data. This demonstrates a deployed app using data from a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rmarkdown with GNIP data</title>
      <link>https://saslaw.github.io/notebooks/rmarkdown-with-gnip-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saslaw.github.io/notebooks/rmarkdown-with-gnip-data/</guid>
      <description>Rnotebook setup This notebook requires a few R packages, listed and loaded below:
pacman::p_load(here, knitr, blogdown, tidyverse, lubridate, kableExtra, ggthemes)  Viewing data I’ve downloaded a small set of data from the International Atomic Energy Agency Global Network for Isotopes in Precipitation that includes water isotope data collected in the last 15 years from 7 sites around the world. The GNIP source doesn’t specify units (!) so I have had to guess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The making of</title>
      <link>https://saslaw.github.io/notebooks/the-making-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saslaw.github.io/notebooks/the-making-of/</guid>
      <description>This is a post about creating this website using Hugo, GitHub, and blogdown for Rmarkdown. There are a number of approaches to this setup, where it starts and which tools to use specifically. My approach is based on prior experience with static site generators, markdown, GitHub, and RStudio. The GitHub repo for this site contains a more detailed history.
Phase One Acceptance I was due for making another work website, and I started with the most obvious option — I made a Wordpress site on my school’s hosting platform.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
