<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on Mae Saslaw</title>
    <link>https://saslaw.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Mae Saslaw</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://saslaw.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum vitae</title>
      <link>https://saslaw.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saslaw.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>Education Expected 2025: Doctor of Philosophy, Geosciences Stony Brook University&#xA;Bachelor of Science, Geology Portland State University 2019&#xA;Bachelor of Fine Arts, Writing Pratt Institute 2009&#xA;Research Graduate Research Assistant Clumped isotope paleoclimate records from Miocene soil carbonates, Turkana Basin, Kenya Stony Brook University Department of Geosciences Fall 2019 – Present&#xA;NSF Research Experience for Undergraduates Stable isotopes of surface water across Sauvie Island, Oregon Portland State University Center for Climate and Aerosol Research Summer 2018</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#GSA2023</title>
      <link>https://saslaw.github.io/meetings/gsa23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saslaw.github.io/meetings/gsa23/</guid>
      <description>Thanks for your interest in my work! See more presentations from the Turkana Miocene Project [link]&#xA;Poster: Insights from ~17 Ma soil carbonate stable isotopes and GCM results in the Turkana Basin, Kenya Coauthors: Daeun Lee, Chris J. Poulsen, Cynthia M. Liutkus-Pierce, Gary E. Stinchcomb, Sara Shedroff, Cat Beck, Craig S. Feibel, Ellen Miller, Gregory A. Henkes</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#AGU21</title>
      <link>https://saslaw.github.io/meetings/agu21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saslaw.github.io/meetings/agu21/</guid>
      <description>My talk: Middle and Late Miocene paleoclimates from clumped isotopes of soil carbonates, Turkana Basin, East Africa Monday, December 13, 13:23 CST, Convention Center - Room 220-222 abstract recording References Almécija, S., Hammond, A. S., Thompson, N. E., Pugh, K. D., Moyà-Solà, S., &amp;amp; Alba, D. M. (2021). Fossil apes and human evolution. Science, 372(6542). https://doi.org/10.1126/science.abb4363 Anyonge, W. (1990). Fauna from a new Lower Miocene locality west of Lake Turkana, Kenya.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://saslaw.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saslaw.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description> Name Email Message Send </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#GSA2022</title>
      <link>https://saslaw.github.io/meetings/gsa22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saslaw.github.io/meetings/gsa22/</guid>
      <description>Thanks for your interest in my work!&#xA;My talk: Soil carbonate clumped isotope temperatures and paleoenvironmental interpretations from the Miocene of the Turkana Basin, East Africa Tuesday, October 11, 2:50 MDT, Convention Center - 207 abstract </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shiny apps with GNIP data</title>
      <link>https://saslaw.github.io/notebooks/shiny-apps-with-gnip-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saslaw.github.io/notebooks/shiny-apps-with-gnip-data/</guid>
      <description>(in progress)&#xA;This is a collection of links to basic Shiny apps using data from the Global Networks of Isotopes in Precipitaion (IAEA/WMO, 2020). Apps are hosted on shinyapps.io, and some of the code can be found across my GitHub repos.&#xA;Level 0 My very first app uses the RStudio sample Shiny code to create an adjustable histogram, with data from GNIP instead of “Old Faithful” sample data. This demonstrates a deployed app using data from a .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The making of</title>
      <link>https://saslaw.github.io/notebooks/the-making-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saslaw.github.io/notebooks/the-making-of/</guid>
      <description>This is a post about creating this website using Hugo, GitHub, and blogdown for Rmarkdown. There are a number of approaches to this setup, where it starts and which tools to use specifically. My approach is based on prior experience with static site generators, markdown, GitHub, and RStudio. The GitHub repo for this site contains a more detailed history.&#xA;Phase One Acceptance I was due for making another work website, and I started with the most obvious option — I made a Wordpress site on my school’s hosting platform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://saslaw.github.io/notebooks/2021-02-20-testing-rmarkdown-with-gnip-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saslaw.github.io/notebooks/2021-02-20-testing-rmarkdown-with-gnip-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt; Rmarkdown with GNIP data Rmarkdown with GNIP data mae 2021-02-20 Rnotebook setup This notebook requires a few R packages, listed and loaded below:&#xA;pacman::p_load(here, knitr, blogdown, tidyverse, lubridate, kableExtra, ggthemes) Viewing data I’ve downloaded a small set of data from the International Atomic Energy Agency Global Network for Isotopes in Precipitation that includes water isotope data collected in the last 15 years from 7 sites around the world. The GNIP source doesn’t specify units (!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
